Guide to the Richard S. Childs Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Richard S. Childs Papers
1918-1977.
Childs, Richard S. (Richard Spencer), b. 1882.
15.5 linear ft (ca. 10,000 items in 37 boxes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library,
MS#0218
4078600
This collection contains correspondence, manuscripts, memoranda, reports, clippings, and other printed materials, 1918-1977, of Richard Spencer Childs.
Biographical Note
Political reformer, publicist. Richard Spencer Childs (1882-1978) was chairman of the National Municipal League, 1931-1978, chairman of the Citizens Union of New York, 1941-1950, president of the Proportional Representation League, and active in many other civic organizations. Among other interests, he promoted the short ballot movement and the city manager plan, and he worked for a responsible election process.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, memoranda, reports, clippings, and other printed materials of Childs.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in two series:
Series I: Correspondence
Series II: Subject File
Subjects
National Municipal League.; Citizens Union of the City of New York.; Proportional Representation League.; United States--Politics and government--20th century.; New York (State)--Politics and government--1865-1951.; New York (State)--Politics and government--1951-; New York (N.Y.)--Politics and government--1898-1951.; New York (N.Y.)--Politics and government--1951-; Reformers.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1982 M-82 National Municipal League Gift
Gift of the National Municipal League, 1982.
- Series I: Correspondence
  - 1968-1977 (Box 1)
  - (Bound Carbons), 1970-1974 (Box 2-4)
- Series II: Subject File
  - Abstracts of state constitutional provisions... Working papers, 1966-1967 (Box 5)
  - Bollens, John C., 1974-1975 (Box 5)
  - The Brookings Institution, 1954-1956 (Box 5)
  - Childs, Richard S.: articles, reports, and personal, 1918-1974 (Box 5)
  - Citizens Union of the City of New York, 1948-1974 (Box 6)
  - Civic victories... By R.S.C. Later working papers, 1952-1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee for Modern Courts, Inc., 1964-1965 (Box 7)
  - Coroner reform (and, Best states for murder. By R.S.C.), 1955-1975 (Box 8)
  - County Manager/Council Manager/City Manager (Box 9)
  - Democratic Party, 1968-1972 (Box 10)
  - Digest of county manager charters and laws. Working papers, 1971-1976 (Box 11)
  - Election systems project, 1971-1973 (Box 11)
  - First 50 years/First 60 years. Working papers, 1970-1973 (Box 11)
  - Independent Citizens' Committee for Goldstein-McGoldrick-Pette, 1945-1946 (Box 11)
  - International City Management Association, 1965-1976 (Box 12)
  - Judges and judicial reform, 1918-1976 (Box 13-15)
  - League of Women Voters - addresses (Box 16)
  - Lehigh University, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Lost causes, 1949-1973 (Box 16)
  - Misc. data re. book, 1970-1971 (Box 16)
  - Misc. "No answer", 1968-1971 (Box 16)
  - Misc. outgoing circulars, 1968-1969 (Box 16)
  - Marshalls - the abolition of city marshalls, 1962-196? (Box 17)
  - Model election systems (Model..., Conn, challenge primary, etc.) (Box 18-21)
  - Model elections - literacy tests (Box 22)
  - New York primary, 1965-1976 (Box 23)
  - Political Science Caucus (Caucus for a New Political Science), 1969-1977 (Box 23)
  - New York State Charter Revision Commission (Decentralization, schools, etc.), 1970-1977 (Box 24-26)
  - Presidential primaries (Presidential nominations, other primaries, etc.), 1956-1960 (Box 27-29)
  - Public Education Association (Box 30)
  - Questionnaires
    - re precinct realities - state party headquarters, 1971-1972 (Box 30)
    - re. pre-primary guidance, 1971 (Box 30)
  - Returnable deposit in New Mexico and Detroit, 1966-1973 (Box 30)
  - School elections, 1969-1975 (Box 30)
  - Short ballot, 1961 (Box 31)
  - State government pitch, 1954 (Box 31)
  - State party structures and procedures., 1966-1968 (Box 31-34)
  - State party structures (Inside 100 state parties.), 1969-1976 (Box 35)
  - Unfinished political reforms., 1974-1976 (Box 36-37)
  - Misc. (Box 36-37)